Contact

302-747-6080 (Mobile) patricia_dark@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/patricia-butts (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Travel Nursing
Emergency Services
Critical Care

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Family Nurse Practitioner

Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner - Adult/Adolescent (SANE)

Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS)

Basic Life Support for Healthcare Providers (BLS)

Honors-Awards

Nurse of the Year - Nurse Graduate

Patricia Dark

MSN, APRN, FNP-BC

Houston, Texas Area

Summary

Proficient, competent, and ambitious family nurse practitioner caring for patients aged from birth to elderly with acute, chronic, and episodic illnesses. Vast experience in multiple emergency departments as a registered nurse from rural to level I teaching centers and pediatric specific hospitals that has helped shape and enhance current practice.

Educated as a Family Nurse Practitioner to care for individuals of all ages. My goal is to use my knowledge, expertise, and compassion to provide excellent, evidence-based care to my patient population and to continue to provide forensic nursing and medicolegal services to local/statewide communities. I am driven to become a leader in the Advanced Practice Registered Nurse community by continuing to advocate for legislative and policy changes granting APRNs full practice authority in all states and by working towards improving education for APRNs.

Experience

Urgent Care for Kids Family Nurse Practitioner June 2019 - Present (1 year)

The Woodlands, TX

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (UTHealth)

Family Nurse Practitioner September 2018 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Spring, Texas

Huntsville Memorial Hospital Family Nurse Practitioner July 2018 - Present (1 year 11 months)

Huntsville, Texas

American Traveler

Registered Nurse

September 2014 - June 2018 (3 years 10 months)

Provided safe, competent, and evidence-based care to all age populations within an emergency department setting in a variety of locations across the United States. Locations ranged from Level I ACS Verified Trauma Centers and specialized Pediatric Trauma Centers to rural and Critical Access Hospitals.

McLeod Health

Registered Nurse

December 2016 - December 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Loris, South Carolina

Beebe Healthcare

Registered Nurse

January 2014 - September 2014 (9 months)

Lewes, DE

Provided nursing care in a 32 bed, level-III trauma center and emergency department with a 4:1 patient/nursing ratio averaging approximately 80,000 patients per year

Bayhealth

Registered Nurse <- LPN <- Unit Secretary
October 2004 - January 2014 (9 years 4 months)

Dover, DE

Registered Nurse

- Provided nursing care in a 40 bed, level-III trauma center and emergency department with a 4:1 patient/nursing ratio averaging approximately 90,000 patients per year
- Served as chair for the department's Shared Governance committee acting as a liaison between nursing leadership and the department's staff to facilitate positive changes for the department

Licensed Practical Nurse

Performed duties as a licensed practical nurse outlined by the State of Delaware Nurse Practice Act in the urgent care setting of the emergency department

Unit Secretary

- Acted as administrative personnel to support all staff within the emergency department
- Regulated a multiline phone system to intercept calls coming to the emergency department and addressed the calls appropriately within a timely manner
- Managed provider order entry to coordinate patient and interdisciplinary care

Education

The University of Texas at Arlington

Pediatric Nurse Practitioner - Acute Care (2019 - 2021)

Walden University

Master of Science (M.S.), Nursing · (2015 - November 2017)

Walden University

Bachelor of Science, Nursing · (2015 - 2016)

Delaware Technical and Community College

Associate of Arts and Sciences (A.A.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2007 - 2011)